Abhishek Sharma

Kolkata, West Bengal, India



sharma.abhishek1282000@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/abhishek-sharma-aa06a9183

Summary

I am Python Developer as well as a Data Analytics. I am passionate about Machine Learning. I have worked on various projects and upgrading myself day by day. Apart from that, I love to engage myself with problem-solving and competitive coding on various platforms.

Here are some of my achievements,

- 6 Star Gold Badge in Problem Solving (HackerRank)
- 4 Star at CodeChef
- 2 Star at LeetCode
- ◆ #3 Global Rank in Coding Blocks
- ◆ #538 Global Rank in Coding Ninjas
- ◆ #9935 Global Rank in InterviewBit
- ◆ #1 UEMK Campus Rank in InterviewBit

Fun Fact about me, I have engaged myself in competitive coding so much that I forget my syllabus oriented studies.:(

Experience



Software Engineer

Learnbird Innovative Solutions

Aug 2020 - Present (6 months +)



Campus Ambassador (Begineer Level)

Collegedunia

Sep 2020 - Present (5 months +)



Campus Ambassador (Master Level)

Collegedunia

Oct 2020 - Present (4 months +)



Data Science and Business Analytics

The Sparks Foundation

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021 (2 months)



Social Media Marketing Specialist

LUDIFU (Let Us Do It For U)

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020 (2 months)

Campus Ambassador (Jedi Level)

Collegedunia

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020 (2 months)

📆 Online Tutor

Samagra Foundation

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020 (2 months)



📘 Marketing Intern

Campus24

Aug 2020 - Sep 2020 (2 months)

I have worked here as a marketing intern where I have got the BEST PERFORMANCE AWARD on the basis of my punctuality and hard work

Accenture Discovery Program

Accenture

Aug 2020 - Aug 2020 (1 month)

Engineering: Undergraduate & Masters Asia Virtual Experience Program

Microsoft

Aug 2020 - Aug 2020 (1 month)

Data Analytics Support

KPMG

Aug 2020 - Aug 2020 (1 month)



Student Intern

NiiT

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020 (8 months)

Education



University of Engineering & Management (UEM)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2019 - 2023



Ramakrishna Mission Boys' Home High School (H.S.), Rahara

Higher Secondary

2017 - 2019

Ramakrishna Mission Boys' Home High School (H.S.) Rahara

Secondary

Ramakrishna Vivekananda Mission, Barrackpore 2008 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications

- Skill assesment test Python (Basic) HackerRank B8BAB6CAC7F6
- Skill Assesment Test on problem Solving (Basic) HackerRank 8461def53765
- Skill Assessment Test Java (Basic) HackerRank
 E9AFED697B69
- **Google Cloud Platform Business Professional Accreditation** Google 56121772
- Google Digital Unlocked Digital Marketing Fundamentals Google Digital Unlocked
 7FK BN5 GUY
- Elements of Al Google Digital Garage
 7hfjef9blt5
- Digital Skills : Artificial Intelligence Accenture 85v3egi
- Microsoft Advertising Certified Professional Microsoft 08a0cd1a-e221-4b3e-b382-0c64c003a3ef
- Introduction to Creative AI Accenture fbryl7p
- Covid 19 Contact Tracing Johns Hopkins Medicine
- Applied Data Science with Python Level 2 IBM
- Data Science Methodologies IBM

- IBM Blockchain Essentials V2 IBM
- Build Your Own Chatbot Level 1 IBM
- Deep Learning Essentials IBM
- Data Analysis Using Python IBM
- Cloud Core IBM
- Data Visualization Using Python IBM
- Machine Learning with Python Level 1 IBM
- Python for Data Science IBM
- Mathematics for Machine Learning : Specialization Certificate Imperial College London

 VDDRS7E92M7P
- AWS Fundamentals Specialization Amazon Web Services (AWS) W856ZJJVLQZ4
- W Machine Learning Specialization University of Washington XYRCYAHZWND4
- Learning Python LinkedIn AVTXdazbiQEXcf8tYG_-z_em-skk

Skills

Machine Learning • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Data Analysis • Data Visualization • Data Science • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Python (Programming Language) • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • C (Programming Language) • Git

Honors & Awards

Applied Data Science with Python - Level 2 - IBM

Aug 2020

Applied Data Science with Python level 2 Badge is issued by IBM after completing their Python related all the E-learning courses and Examinations

- Best Marketing Intern at Campus24 Campus24
 Sep 2020
 In the internship period, I have achieved the best performance award from the respective company
- 5 Star Gold Badge in Python Programming Language Hackerrank Sep 2020
- 5 Star Gold Badge in C language (HackerRank) HackerRank Sep 2020
- 6 Star Gold Badge in Problem Solving Programming HackerRank Sep 2020